So let's talk about boundaries. Here's an excerpt from my latest book, Body Waping Through the BS.
Crank that through an S.A. S.A. stands for sexual assault.
I did not know it then, but my addressing my aunt's remixing of our convos was setting a boundary.
Telling my mom I needed to step back from communication post S.A. because she was not supporting me in a way that was helpful was a boundary.
I define boundaries as the self-imposed limits of tolerance to other people's shit.
Everybody got shit. Few are sifting through it.
Instead, they are devolving into primates and throwing they shit at everyone, projecting all over the place.
This is why you can't take anything personal, but you also don't have to take it on.
Boundaries are not passive aggressive attacks.
They are the energy force fields you engage to limit the effects of people's projections.
Unfortunately, instead of letting the boundary inspire self-reflection, more often than not, boundaries piss people off who have never had them with you before.
The lack of access to affecting you feels like an attack because that boundary force field repels that shit right back at them with the same force they were projecting it.
Bam! In the face!
The truth hurts.
However, unless your boundaries come from a pure place, they might just be acts of avoidance.
So be honest with yourself.
You see, the truth and telling it is an incredibly difficult and courageous act in a world that does not honor the truth.
Because it doesn't just hurt the person that is receiving it.
It can hurt the person that is telling it.
In some cases, it hurts your career.
It hurts your relationship.
It also can physically hurt your body.
Now, the thing about boundaries is that they create a separation.
And when you are tied to someone or a situation, whether it be spiritually, physically, emotionally, chemically,
the erection of a boundary is going to be felt by both of you.
And when you tell the truth, you are creating a boundary.
This is one of the reasons why I believe so many battered women end up going back.
Now, as far as being a truth teller and truth receiver, that ain't no light work.
That boundary isn't just a separation between you and somebody.
When you are speaking the truth, you're making a boundary between you and the world that is constantly trying to eat your energy.
That is constantly trying to manipulate your frequency.
And you're saying no.
And speaking the truth is literally a boundary against that.
Because what we are experiencing on a daily basis is a complete manipulation of what's true.
So I send out to all of you all the power to save the course.
To tell necessary truths.
Whether they build difficult boundaries or not.
And how do you know what's a necessary truth?
Because it's one that frees people.
There are boundaries that have been erected literally overnight since I put this out.
Not just boundaries with the world.
Boundaries with individuals that were a part of my world.
My body is physically impaired right now.
Because I am dealing with the chemical reaction to separation.
You know the abandonment issues everybody talk about?
Yeah, even once you've decoded them, your body can still react in fight or flight.
Because it's been trained to do so.
You, your soul, has to override.
The separation anxiety that's in my body is physically an impairment.
And it is only through so much goddamn therapy that I have the mental and soul fortitude
to not let that pain shift me from what I know is the right thing to do.
And I send that and I wish that strength and clarity for you.
Thank you for all the kind words you all shared yesterday under my post.
And thank you for supporting this work.
Body Waving Through the Bullshit, Crank That Through an Essay,
is available at amandalandexports.com.
Thank you.